<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intro to VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Operations – Course Introduction</title><link>https://modernappsninja.github.io/tkoplaceholder_tk8606/docs/courseintroduction/</link><description>Recent content in Course Introduction on Intro to VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Operations</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 18:34:25 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://modernappsninja.github.io/tkoplaceholder_tk8606/docs/courseintroduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Welcome to the Course</title><link>https://modernappsninja.github.io/tkoplaceholder_tk8606/docs/courseintroduction/welcometothecourse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 18:34:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://modernappsninja.github.io/tkoplaceholder_tk8606/docs/courseintroduction/welcometothecourse/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Welcome to the Tanzu Kubernetes Operations Course. On behalf of the VMware Modern Applicaiotns Team we thank you for your time in taking this course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few Notes before we begin:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Some of the links in this course will only work for VMware employees as they are behind the VMware corporate firewall.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In launching a hyperlink please RIGHT click on the link and select &amp;ldquo;open link in new tab&amp;rdquo; to avoid having the link for this course overlayed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This course provides a technical introduction to VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Operations (TKO)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tanzu for Kubernetes Operations (TKO) is a marketing bundle that aims to meet the needs of on-premise and public cloud infrastructure teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TKO addresses Developer self-service to the right infrastructure abstraction and app building blocks:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Automation and monitoring of cloud platform operations&lt;br>
Enforcement of Networking, security and compliance requirements&lt;br>
Platform operation cost optimization&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two solution bundles are offered:&lt;br>
The TKO Data Center bundle and the TKO Public Cloud bundle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Data center bundle includes all of the Public cloud bundle but has tools and tech for vSphere, e.g. AVI Enterprise.
VMware Internal Bundle Page (&lt;a href="https://confluence.eng.vmware.com/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=1130565069">https://confluence.eng.vmware.com/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=1130565069&lt;/a>) &lt;strong>NOTE this is a VMware Internal Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tanzu Mission Control (TMC) Advanced - Includes additional functionality around policies. (&lt;a href="https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-Tanzu-Mission-Control/services/tanzumc-concepts/GUID-2CA211CD-E62C-46E1-918F-B511C80F906D.html">https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-Tanzu-Mission-Control/services/tanzumc-concepts/GUID-2CA211CD-E62C-46E1-918F-B511C80F906D.html&lt;/a>)&lt;br>
Tanzu Service Mesh (TSM) Advanced - The base offering of TSM. TSM Enterprise is the upgraded offering providing additional features. See Link highlighting TSM Advanced vs Enterprise editions.&lt;br>
Antrea Advanced - Offers Tier RBAC policy control and Wavefront Integration. See Datasheet for different Antrea offerings and details. See tech talk on Antrea Networking &amp;amp; Tier RBAC.a&lt;br>
AVI Enterprise (aka AVI Vantage/NSX Advanced Load Balancer) - Full featured L7 Container Ingress with WAF support for On-Premise. See Datasheet for complete feature list and editions comparison.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you for investing your time!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>=======&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7nmfkembjmc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Prerequisites For The Tanzu For Kubernetes Operations Course</title><link>https://modernappsninja.github.io/tkoplaceholder_tk8606/docs/courseintroduction/prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 18:34:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://modernappsninja.github.io/tkoplaceholder_tk8606/docs/courseintroduction/prerequisites/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We recommend taking the &lt;a href="https://lms.modernapps.ninja/courses/course-v1:modernapps+COU-TP6539+Perpetual/course/">Introduction to VMware Tanzu
Portfolio&lt;/a> course
prior to taking this course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course assumes familiarity witha the basic components which make up Tanzu Kubernetes Operations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tanzu Kubernetes Grid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tanzu Mission Control&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tanzu Observability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tanzu Service Mesh&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Avi/NSX Load Balancer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you do not have a conversational level of knowledge about these technologies you may benefit from reviewing the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (&lt;a href="https://tanzu.vmware.com/kubernetes-grid">https://tanzu.vmware.com/kubernetes-grid&lt;/a>) and the Hands On Lab #2234&lt;br>
For Tanzu Mission Control (&lt;a href="https://tanzu.vmware.com/mission-control">https://tanzu.vmware.com/mission-control&lt;/a>) and the Hands On Lab #2234&lt;br>
For Tanzu Observability
For Tanzu Service Mesh
For Avi: (&lt;a href="https://avinetworks.com/education/">https://avinetworks.com/education/&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may also want to familarize yourself with the Tanzu portfolio and TKO labs on Pathfinder:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tanzu Standard [https://pathfinder.vmware.com/path/tanzu_standard] (&lt;a href="https://pathfinder.vmware.com/path/tanzu_standard">https://pathfinder.vmware.com/path/tanzu_standard&lt;/a>)&lt;br>
TKO (&lt;a href="https://pathfinder.vmware.com/v3/path/tko_path">https://pathfinder.vmware.com/v3/path/tko_path&lt;/a>)&lt;br>
AVI/NSX Load Balancer (&lt;a href="https://pathfinder.vmware.com/v3/path/nsxbc">https://pathfinder.vmware.com/v3/path/nsxbc&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additonally some familarity with Kubernetes and Cloud Native
Technologies. If you are not familiar with these technologies, we
recommend checking out &lt;a href="https://kube.academy/">KubeAcademy&lt;/a> by VMware,
which has a terrific set of free, bite-size video resources on the
basics of containers, Kubernetes and cloud native that are great for
beginners.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before taking this course, you should also have familiarity with vSphere
administration. If you need additional background in vSphere, we
recommend checking out &lt;a href="https://hol.vmware.com">VMware Hands on Labs&lt;/a>,
which offers a number of vSphere labs and content including labs which cover TKO and the components which comprise the bundle.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>